NAVRAJ SINGH KAMBO

Burnaby, BC | nkambo1@my.bcit.ca | linkedin.com/in/navrajkambo/

CAREER SUMMARY

Junior Electrical Engineer with 1 year of combined experience working in industrial environments, primarily focused on implementation of communications systems and R&D. Excellent interpersonal and communication abilities, and possess a wide range of technical skills. Enjoys being part of a team, and thrives in high pressure and challenging working environments.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS AND CORE COMPETENCIES

- · Knowledgeable in AC (single and three phase) and DC electronic circuit theory
- · Insightful in control theory, and industrial control system design (Siemens PLC and DeltaV DCS)
- · Experience with control valve sizing, sensor selection, and instrumentation signalling (ISA 5.1)

Modeling and Analysis
Software & Tools

AutoCad, SolidWorks, Fusion 360, MATLAB, LTSpice, git, SKM, ETAP MS Office, LATEX, Altium Designer, Python, C++, JavaScript, Verilog

EDUCATION

British Columbia Institute of Technology, Burnaby

Bachelor in Engineering, Electrical Graduated with Distinction

September 2015 - May 2019 Overall GPA: 85%

WORK EXPERIENCE

British Columbia Institute of Technology, Burnaby

May 2018 - August 2018

Research Intern

- · Created a working prototype of a cross-platform mobile application (iOS Android) for use in Haiti on concrete bricks
- · Carried out peak-finding algorithm development associated with concrete testing
- · Implemented and debugged time-domain impulse detection algorithm for mobile devices
- · Learned the React-Native extension of JavaScript, and basic Java

${\bf Wireless\ Technical\ Services\ Inc.,\ Coquitlam}$

April 2017 - August 2017

Co-op Student

- · Worked on the Fortis BC Radio Network (FBCRN) project, including helping point out a possible vulnerability using software defined radio (SDR) technology
- · Designed and implemented software in python for network device convenience and maintenance
- · Carried out Rack Acceptance Tests (RATs) for quality assurance purposes
- · Worked with various hand and power tools when manufacturing a communications rack

BKS Cablecom Ltd., Burnaby

May 2016 - August 2016

Jr. Technician

- · Installed, and tested data cabling for data and voice systems
- · Labeled and assembled patch panel assemblies, and upgraded wireless networking equipment
- · Terminated AMP and Belden shielded/unshielded category cables with proprietary tools
- \cdot Worked along side Sr Technicians, Electricians and UBC IT services on various projects
- · Learned and applied de-facto standards in the telecommunications installation industry

Autonomous Vineyard Harvesting

Our senior engineering capstone group aimed to improve on current grape picking systems by developing a robotic vehicle that can harvest grape crops autonomously and selectively. It was required to navigate a vineyard without the need for human intervention, work during all times of the day, and successfully detect and harvest wine grape crops using cutting-edge vision technologies, robotics, and various engineering methods we've acquired at BCIT.

Heat Exchanger Modeling and Controller Design

As part of the Industrial Control Systems course at BCIT, I was tasked with designing a temperature-flow cascade control strategy to regulate the outlet water temperature of a particular gas-liquid heat exchanger, incorporating disturbances such as steam header pressure, inlet water temperature, and water flow-rate. A model of the heat exchanger was also created in a DeltaV virtual machine.

Automated Writing Utensil

For my embedded systems term project, I designed and implemented a simple P-D controller for two Quanser SRV02 motors using a real-time embedded system (TMS320F28027). Parts were fabricated (PLA printing) to allow a pen to draw anywhere within a $36in^2$ square. This project involved interfacing the RTES to external hardware including power amplifiers and quadrature encoders, through the use of various communications standards (SPI & SCI for example).

Self Driving Maze Navigation Car

In a group of 2, my partner and I were able to design and implement a self driving car that was able to solve a maze. The maze included colored markers to indicate turning directions, requiring the use of computer vision. A custom PCB was assembled to hold components needed for the vehicle.

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

- · 2019 BCIT Student Innovation Challenge: 2nd place
- · 2018 NSERC Undergraduate Student Research Award (USRA) recipient
- · 2017 APEGBC Scholarship recipient
- · 2015 Burnaby Central Alumni Scholarship, Top student Electronics 10 and PE 12
- \cdot 2014 Vancouver High School Science Olympics Eastern league event: $1^{\rm st}$ place

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Guru Nanak's Free Kitchen, East Vancouver

September 2013 - Present

Dishwasher

- · Serving lunch to residents of Vancouver's downtown east side
- · Assisting with washing and cleanup before and after lunch
- · Working along side church and community center staff

EXTRA-CURRICULAR INTERESTS

- · Snowboarding
- · Playing and watching soccer & basketball
- · 3D printing knick-knacks
- · Participating in the Sun Run
- · Road and mountain biking enthusiast